<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Obsidian Vault]]></title><description><![CDATA[Obsidian digital garden]]></description><link>http://github.com/dylang/node-rss</link><image><url>site-lib/media/favicon.png</url><title>Obsidian Vault</title><link></link></image><generator>Webpage HTML Export plugin for Obsidian</generator><lastBuildDate>Mon, 25 Aug 2025 22:22:08 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="site-lib/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><pubDate>Mon, 25 Aug 2025 22:22:08 GMT</pubDate><ttl>60</ttl><dc:creator></dc:creator><item><title><![CDATA[Diary of a CEO Intro Breakdown Update]]></title><description><![CDATA[
Episodes begin with ~ 1:30s - 2:00m sizzle reel consisting of engaging highlights of the episode. These clips are not related to the order in which they are discussed in the episode, it seems. Whatever is most engaging comes first. There are several different sections of these introductions; different "in and out" points. The first 5 seconds of each episode is the first in and out. This is the first "gate" so-to-speak in the episode. We can imagine these "gates" as part of the sales pitch from the creator to the consumer. A "gate" is a moment in the episode where a viewer may tune out; it is the job of the edit to bring the viewer through each gate using creative &amp; engaging techniques. Each hook, each in and out use different techniques to bring viewers past each gate. They are seemingly editing the first 2 minutes of each episode in the style of short form content (TikTok, YT shorts). They get the viewer past the first gate with a 5 second edit, then a 10-20 second edit to pass the second gate, etc.. They ramp up the content length and context from short form to long from in the 2 minute intro until they get to the final long format of the show. - The initial hook can last anywhere from 5 seconds to 30 seconds
- Next, the guest is introduced, quick bio
- Third hook is introduced, leading question indicating discussion to be had
- Fourth hook, guest reveals their platform and basis for their attendance
- Fifth hook, rapid fire quick cuts of host and guest back and forth answering engaging questions, not expound upon
- Appeal to emotion
- CTA
- Long-form Often opens with pointed question <img alt="Pasted image 20250824132100.png" src="pastes/pasted-image-20250824132100.png" target="_self"> <br><a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=giT0ytynSqg" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=giT0ytynSqg" target="_self">0:00-0:06 -- "Godfather of AI: I Tried to Warn Them, But We've Already Lost Control! Geoffrey Hinton"</a> Or, something ambiguous/ mysterious <br>
<img alt="Pasted image 20250824130511.png" src="pastes/pasted-image-20250824130511.png" target="_self"> <br><a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=yfEQRqFo2bI" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=yfEQRqFo2bI" target="_self">0:00-0:05 -- Neuroscientist (Dr. Tara Swart): Evidence We Can Communicate After Death!</a> Subtitles are creatively placed throughout the reel to emphasize talking points and 'hooks' Creative use of "Godfather" branding when talking to 'Godfather of AI' Engages video audience
<br><img alt="Pasted image 20250824123158.png" src="pastes/pasted-image-20250824123158.png" target="_self">
Important part of the initial 5 second hook Host is represented by yellow text, while guest is represented by white
Always moving, fast paced cuts, zooms, blurs, effects
Subtitles are laid out in chunks or word by word, never the whole sentence at once
Placed all around the frame, much like a comic book rather than a novel Kareoke-esque subtitles to punctuate engaging points Sharp, quick, effective
Always moving. Often 5+ cuts in the first 10 seconds
Cut to different angle, b-roll, effect zoom, blur, wipe, transitions Effect usage Often opens on split-screen of guest and host, pseudo thumbnail <br><img alt="Pasted image 20250824141058.png" src="pastes/pasted-image-20250824141058.png" target="_self"> Moving background vfx to entertain video audience Creative B-roll to illustrate the guest's monologue and keep up pace of visual stimulus Diary of a CEO doesn't even use its own name in the title; no episode number, nothing. Straight to engagement bait, titled as a short even though 2hrs long Godfather of AI: I Tried to Warn Them, But We’ve Already Lost Control! Geoffrey Hinton Neuroscientist (Dr. Tara Swart): Evidence We Can Communicate After Death! Proven Playbook For Quitting Your 9-5 In 9 Months! (Fastest Way To Financial Freedom) Mohnish Pabrai Brain Experts WARNING: Watch This Before Using ChatGPT Again! (Shocking New Discovery) Constant use of risers and impacts to build and release tension Riser Impact (TURN VOLUME DOWN BEFORE PLAYING CLIP BELOW) Sub Impact Often unnoticed by viewer but go a long in keeping attention Sound fx are often used to punctuate what speaker is saying and add some flare Most VFX are also punctuated with sounds like we see below (mouse clicking noises, risers, wooshes, impacts, glitch noises, notification sounds) Impact Buzz Glitch &amp; Riser/ Woosh Woosh Riser/ Woosh &amp; Glitch - - In just 9 seconds we see the use of several sound effects. SFX are used constantly to keep the viewer's attention The mysterious but playful instrumental theme is usually played at the beginning of the longform segment of the show, marking the transition. Even if viewers skip the 2 minute introduction using the timestamps, they will always hear the theme at the start of the longform section. This creates another component that the show can be identified by.
]]></description><link>diary-of-a-ceo-intro-breakdown-update.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Work/Diary Breakdown/Diary of a CEO Intro Breakdown Update.md</guid><pubDate>Mon, 25 Aug 2025 22:20:23 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="." length="0" type="false"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;.&quot;&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item></channel></rss>